Sales Enquiry/Helpline

1800 102 2558 | +91 9818882211







Director with a strong experience of executing application and system development projects for fortune 500

clients across telecom, healthcare, banking.19 years of experience in design, development and testing with 9 years in project management

Current Designation: Director Total Experience: 19 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: HiveMaven Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: Post Graduate Diploma [Telecom Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Management - Specialization in Systems]

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Head/VP/GM-Technology(IT)/CTO Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Core Java, J2Ee, Angularjs, Node.Js, React.Js, Express.js, Bootstrap, Spring Framework, Hibernate, Oracle

Database, MongoDB, Postgres, Docker, Jenkins, Lucene, Solr, Elastic Search

Verified : Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Jump to Section

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Summary

Director with a strong experience of executing application and system development projects for fortune 500 clients across USA, UK, and Europe. Development experience of systems, applications, and products to provide solutions across verticals like telecom, healthcare, banking, and life insurance. Recognised by organisations for strong project management experience of executing and delivering complex projects as per timelines, budget, and quality. 19 years of strong experience in design, development and testing with 10 years of project management experience of managing projects through effective communication and stakeholder management

Work Experience

HiveMaven as Director him 2010 to Till Date

Jun 2019 to Till Date

Hive Maven is a social networking website where users generate and give access to unlimited information on various topics and industry verticals and information sharing is promoted through maven and monetization programs. Mavens share information on topics specific to their knowledge area or expertise and are rated based on the knowledge area, level of information shared, level of engagement and customer traffic generated. The website promotes focussed groups, social networking groups and maven groups which can be used for revenue generation by branding, affiliate marketing, business promotions, marketing campaigns, influencer marketing etc and user monetization

Role: Director

Skills: Angular, Node.js, Express.js, ,HTML5, CSS, Mongo DB, JSON, Jasmine, Karma, Protractor, Bootstrap, Docker, Redis, Jenkins, Elastic Search, AWS EC2, AWS Lambda, AWS VPC, AWS EBS, AWS Cloud Formation, AWS IAM,

Role Description:

- ? Responsible for planning, estimation, architecture, and end-end delivery of the solution
- ? Provide strategic guidance and direction to development team.
- ? Subject matter expert to provide mentoring and technical direction to development team.
- ? Identify market gaps, requirements or issues and increase user experience for the product.
- ? Ensure team implements techniques, user experience and best practices with required documentation
- ? Hire a high performing team and engage teams to provide the required solution.

Cognizant Technology Solutions

Jan 2013 to Jun 2019

Project # 1: Prudential, USA

Project Description:

Prudential application consolidates the direct and indirect sales channels through digital strategy. The sales channels consolidation helped to increase customer value proposition, customer acquisition, customer retention and net revenue and thereby increasing the sales and profitability of life insurance packages and policies Role: Project Manager

Skills: Node js, Express js, Angular, HTML5, CSS, REST Webservices, Mongo DB, Jasper reports, JSON, Jasmine,



Important

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld. Karma, Protractor, Jenkins, Bootstrap, Vaadin, Docker, XML, EHCache, JMeter

360-degree customer view by integrating with direct and indirect sales channels for unified view of customer Usage base insurance analysis using Telematics, Data aggregation of Policy aggregators and Routing analysis for

risk management and call centre operation optimization through Call centre integration
Customer events, triggering events and Urchin Tracking module (UTM) to analyse customer preferences, website customer events and marketing campaigns leading to policy sales respectively

Role Description:

Deriving the Project Plan and schedule of the project to deliver the project within the given timelines

Responsible for managing the cost of the project and deliver the project within the defined budget

Stakeholder management and risk management for communicating weekly status and resolving risks and issues respectively for the project.

Team Management for mentoring and assessing team members and appraisal of the resources on project performance

Project #2: Barclays Bank, USA Project Description:

The application enabled the growth and sales of portfolio management services unit through digital strategy. It helped in customer acquisition and customer asset maximisation and there by leading to higher customer lifetime value and net revenue of Barclays

Role: Project Manager

Skills: React.js, Node.js, HTML5, CSS, REST Webservices, Mongo DB, Jasper reports, Elastic search, EHCache JSON, Jest, Enzyme, Cypress, Jenkins, Bootstrap, Vaadin, Docker, XML, JMeter, Twilio

Digital marketing analysis including E-mail marketing and Mobile marketing (SMS integration), Customer online journey maps to analyse digital onboarding customer experience, Interactive online assistant for risk monitoring of customer portfolio

Responsive website to enhance digital experience and Web analytics for Visitor characterisation, Content characterization and E-marketing to track customer behaviour and customer closure events

Deriving the Project Plan and schedule of the project to deliver the project within the given timelines

Define, monitor, and improve critical to success metrics for the success of the project

Escalation management and risk management to identify, assess, track and mitigate issues and risks Interact with Business and Project Stakeholders to define and deliver complex features and ensure consistent and transparent status updates to all stakeholders

Project #3: NetApp, USA Project Description:

The application helped Net App increase the customer experience across multi-channel support, providing the customer a consistent experience while buying their product and solutions. The application helped NetApp use multichannel support to customers in reducing time-to-resolution, increasing customer satisfaction and strengthening customer loyalty.

Role: Project Manager

Skills: React js, Node js, HTML5, CSS, REST Webservices, Mongo DB, Jasper reports, JSON, Jest, Enzyme, Cypress, Jenkins, Bootstrap, Vaadin, Docker, XML, JMeter, REDIS Cache, Elastic Search, Adobe Experience Manager Funnel visualization used analyse website goal and Multi-channel funnels (MCF) to report the analysis of source, referrals, and landing page to conversion user information, durations, destinations and downloads

Ericsson Global Business Services

Jan 2012 to Dec 2012

Project #1: Etisalat, Dubai

Project Description:

Etisalat's service monitoring system allows for proactive response, data security and data gathering and the overall good health of a telecom services and while monitoring does not fix problems, it does lead to more stable and reliable telecom network to help provide customers with good service quality

Role: Project Manager

Skills: Java, CORBA, RM, HTML, XML, JSON, JMX, Object Request Broker (ORB), DOM4j, EJB, CMP, Dynamic TMN, SNMP4J, Java Mail, JDBC, SQL, LDAP, JMS

24x7 real time service monitoring and MP monitoring to track the services of important customers for compliance issues

Data and voice services quality monitoring and Roaming service management to track network performance and quality of service provided to roaming customers and subscribers

Service degraded customer spots data to identify location to improve service availability

Role Description:

Project team building, staffing and recruitment to onboard resources and recruit team members

Risk management for the management for the project to track risks and issues and derive mitigation plans for the project

Accenture

May 2010 to Dec 2011

1. Project Description: Contact Centre Solutions, CISCO, USA

Accenture and Cisco strategic alliance focused on CISCO enabled solution for implementing value-added services to end users. The strategic long-term partnership provides end-end and packaged offerings to telecom customers by developing Java based version of Agent desktop

Designation: Project Lead

Skills: Java, Java CTI Client interface libraries, XML, Java Telephony Application Programming Interface (JTAPI), RMI, JMS. CORBA. SOAP. HTML. SQL

Solution provides self-service interactive voice response (IVR) and multi-channel automated call distribution (ACD), combined with built-in Context Service for simplified customer journey and outbound campaign management. Contact centre agent and supervisor desktop API for customization and centralization of a single workspace application Engage with customers on a variety of channels from a single intuitive contact centre agent desktop that includes inbound voice, outbound voice, outbound IVR, and digital channels.

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from Madras University, Sri Venkateshwara College of Engineering in

PG: Post Graduate Diploma (Telecom Management - Specialization in Systems) from Symbiosis Institute of Telecom Management in 2000

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Angular, Node.js, Express, React.js			
Core Java, J2EE, Spring, Hibernate			
REST, SOAP, JSP			
JSON, AJAX, JavaScript, PL/SQL			
XML, AJAX, HTML5, JQuery			
Java Mail , JTA , JPA , JAXB			
CORBA, RMI, JMX, EJB, DOM			
SAX, DOM, Log4j , Apache OpenNLP			
Elastics Search, Redis Search, EH Cache			
Solr Search, Lucene Search, Elastic Searc			
Spring Framework , Hibernate			
Linux, Unix, Windows			
Tomcat, Weblogic, WebSphere			
Oracle 9i, Oracle 11g, Postgres			
MySQL, Geolite2, MongoDB, Oracle, Postgres			
Rational Requisite Pro, Jira, MS Project			
Junit, Mockito, DynaTrace			
JMeter, Loadrunner, SOAP UI			
Docker, Jenkins, Maven, Gradle			
Jest, Enzyme, Cypress			
Docker, Jenkins, Maven, Gradle			
Spring Boot , Spring Security			
Spring Framework , Hibernate			
Checkstyle, Findbugs			
ANT, Jasmine, KARMA, Protractor			
Adobe Experience Manager, Vaadin			
Twilio, Telesign SMS, OpenEMM			
AWS IoT SiteWise			
JTAPI,SWT,Coding Accuracy Support system			
JSP			
EJB, JDBC, JMS, JNDI			
Remedy			

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization
US Work Status: Need H1 Visa

Physically Challenged: No

Category: General

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.